ethnically jewish people are indigenous to the lands of israel oh boy okay so while i think that
creator means well i think it is a gross misrepresentation to start that video with
the claim that all jews ethnically are indigenous to the lands of israel for a couple main reasons
one this creator does not seem to understand what indigeneity means in our modern world and two
there are many different jewish ethnic groups we're not all under the same umbrella and three
that misconception is often used to justify the brutal displacement of palestinians so first
indigeneity indigeneity especially through our modern conception of white supremacy
the way indigenous peoples are colonized in our modern world is more than just an ancient ancestral
tie to a piece of land it is also about power the power imbalance between the colonizer and the
colonized the powerful and the disempowered and so while the lands of israel palestine
do have great religious and cultural significance for jews that does not inherently mean we
as an entire group are indigenous in our modern conception of that term especially when you
think about how the state of israel was created on the forced displacement of 700 000 palestinians
and millions more have been displaced or killed ever since 1948 when the nakba occurred and when you think
about how israel has the entire backing of the western world and its military might when israel is
shutting off water for residents of raza when palestinians are forced to go through israeli
checkpoints every single day to go to work to go to school to just live and israel controls their
passports their entry their movement their entire lives who is the colonizer and who is the colonized
here okay second not all jews are ethnically indigenous to the middle east or palestine specifically
as an ashkenazi jew meaning i'm descended from jews who fled eastern europe i can trace my direct
ancestry to poland to germany to russia to eastern europe but i cannot trace my family history whatsoever
to anywhere in the middle east and sure maybe thousands of years ago people in my direct
ancestral line lived there but why should i have a claim to a piece of land uh just because i'm jewish
like maybe poland owes me but palestinians don't and it's obscene that i as a jew could immigrate to
israel very easily when generation and it's obscene that i as a jewish person could immigrate to israel
pretty easily when generations and generations of palestinians are unable to return to their
ancestral homes to their family histories to the places their grandparents grew up that they can track
but there are jews who are indigenous to the middle east mizrahim middle eastern jews jews who can trace
their family histories to palestine lebanon syria iraq iran etc and there are palestinians who are
also jewish and so they would be jews who are indigenous to the lands of israel and funny enough
lots of jewish palestinian families were also displaced during the nakba and the creation of the
state of israel so ultimately some jews are indigenous in the middle east some are indigenous to palestine
but not all of us are especially when you think about what the term indigenous actually means
and there are a ton of people who are not jewish who are indigenous to palestine there are palestinian
muslims christians and so all indigenous and then three this idea that all jews are indigenous
to the lands of israel has been used to justify the the ongoing nakba to justify the ongoing
displacement of palestinians to claim that we have a better claim to this land because of our
ancestral history thousands of years ago but that is a misappropriation of what indigeneity means
that is a misappropriation of what indigenous justice is separately fun fact when you look at the
history of zionism and like the first talks in the late 19th century about zionism and the creation of a
jewish state they were talking about creating one in uganda or south america it wasn't always going to be
the lands of israel and i think that shows a lot about zionism as a settler colonial project i wish
for a world where jews will feel safe but i don't think that world can be found through violent
occupation and settler colonization and palestine is a beautiful and wonderful place that i have had the
privilege of going and living and working with palestinian activists in i did a bds compliant trip to
the west bank um almost two years ago and i pray for a day where everyone who lives in that land is free
with equal rights where there is no more apartheid and where palestinians are given a full right of
return to their lands that they are indigenous to which does include some jews just not all of us